You don't have to be a hero to do this job. But it helps.
The Hurt Locker is a drama, thriller, war film directed by Kathryn Bigelow.
During the Iraq War, a Sergeant recently assigned to an army bomb squad is put at
odds with his squad mates due to his maverick way of handling his work.
Staff Sergeant William James, played by Jeremy Renner.
Sergeant JT Sanborn, played by Anthony Mackie.
Specialist Owen Eldridge, played by Brian Geraghty.
Colonel Reed, played by David Morse.
Sergeant Matt Thompson, played by Guy Pearce.
Connie James, played by Evangeline Lilly.
The Hurt Locker is a 2008 American war film directed by
Kathryn Bigelow and written by Mark Boal.
It stars Jeremy Renner, Anthony Mackie, Brian Geraghty, Christian
Camargo, Ralph Fiennes, David Morse, and Guy Pearce.
It follows an Iraq War bomb disposal team who are targeted by insurgents and
shows their psychological reactions to the stress of combat.
Boal drew on his experience during embedded access to write the screenplay.
The Hurt Locker premiered at the 2008 Venice International Film Festival and was
released in the United States on June 26, 2009, by Summit Entertainment.
It received positive reviews from critics, who
praised the acting and cinematography.
It was nominated for nine Academy Awards and won six, including Best Director and Best Original
Screenplay, and became the first film directed by a woman to win Best Picture.
It grossed $50 million worldwide.
The Hurt Locker is considered one of the most influential
war films of the 2000s and the 21st century.
In 2020, it was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film explores themes of rescue, sniper, explosive, loyalty, us army.
The tone is emotional and intense.